Łukasz Cieśluk

Personal details

Residence: Dublin, Ireland

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lukaszciesluk

Summary

Professional Java Developer with over six years extensive experience within financial, telco, advertising and commerce industries. Highly self-motivated focused on clean code approach combined with functional programming. Advocate of automation in projects and addicted to open source.

Experience

XII.2017 - current

Senior Software Developer, Bloomberg PolarLake Dublin, Ireland

Enhance Enterprise Data Management to the Financial Markets with Market Index Data (Indices) functionality as separate microservice

Stack: Java 8, Spring (Boot, Data, MVC), Maven, Flyway, Oracle, Guava, JUnit, Mockito, AssertJ, RabbitMQ, Ansible, Swagger, JavaScript, ExtJS

IV.2017 - XI.2017

Senior Software Developer, Datalex Limited Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop application for storing and managing flights and other additional services
- 2. Bring code style within clean code approach and new practices in terms of development and testing
- 3. Compose performance scripts in JMeter
- ${\bf 4.}\ \ {\bf Perform\ code\ reviews\ along\ with\ mentoring\ other\ developers}$

Stack: Java 8, Gradle, RESTEasy, MongoDB, Morphia, JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, JMeter

VIII.2015 - III.2017

Software Developer, Brandtone Limited Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop primary campaign management system that engages consumers through different channels like IVR, SMS and USSD. First developer of Konnect online engagement platform which empowers marketers to maximize ROI and build deep relationships with consumers. Involved in developing Trader solution which helps traders improve selling their products
- 2. Cooperation with QA's, DevOps, DBA's, Architects and other Developers to build software which meets business requirements and KPIs
- 3. Participate in Agile Sprint planning, backlog refinement and retrospectives
- 4. Experience of working in environment which requires excellent troubleshooting, analytical skills, ability to be self-organised, strong interpersonal, communication skills and experience with a number of stack components and tools
- 5. Perform code reviews
- 6. Documentation enhancement

Stack: Java, Spring (MVC, Data, Batch, Integration), Maven, Oracle, Guava, Git, JUnit, Mockito, Grunt, Bower, Flyway, Docker, ActiveMQ, AWS, Angular, React, Redux

VIII.2014 - VI.2015

Senior Java Developer, Digital Virgo S.A. Department of Development and Services Warsaw, Poland

- I. Develop mobile Value Added Services e.g. massive SMS sending service. Design dedicated standalone client for lottery system. Support developers involved in mobiParking project
- 2. Implement SMS Payment Gateways responsible for charging clients for paid content and services
- 3. Collaboration with business analysts to fulfill client requirements and estimate particular modules of system
- 4. Partnership with developers responsible for the frontend
- 5. Preparation of technical and user documentation

Stack: Java, Spring (MVC, Data), Maven, Oracle, Git, Swing, Python

XI.2013 - VII.2014

Software Developer, AgreeYa Mobility Poland Sp. z o.o. Warsaw, Poland

- Develop supply system dedicated to the medical industry in accordance with customer requirements
- 2. Direct collaboration with the client in order to select technologies and solutions applied in the application
- 3. Composition of technical and user documentation of produced software

Stack: Java, Python, Django, JavaScript, jQuery

VII.2012 - X.2013

Software Developer, Bank Gospodarstwa Krajowego Architecture and Monitoring Division Warsaw, Poland

- I. Leading role in incorporate new extensions of system responsible for monitoring bank infrastructure e.g. execution of money transfers, network stability, databases availability and other banking systems
- 2. Support supervisor during the design and implementation of new data models and graphs commissioned by Bank management and other departments
- 3. Overall system administration and maintenance

Stack: Java, Perl, MySQL, Nagios

The intern was founded in XVII edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

VII.20II - IX.20II

Software Developer (intern), Telekomunikacja Polska S.A. Networks and Service Platform Division, Department of Management Platforms Warsaw, Poland

Implement tool improving the efficiency of administrator work around collecting and analysing Call Detail Records (CDR) used for billing customers for paid services

Stack: Java, Perl, PostgreSQL

The intern was founded in XVI edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

VII.2010 - IX.2010

Software Developer (intern), Orange Poland S.A. Networks and Service Platforms Division, Department of ICT Systems Warsaw, Poland

Support administrators in the current surveillance and response to the failure of IT systems responsible for the proper operation of the GSM/UMTS mobile networks. Develop tools to improve and enhance operational efficiency

Stack: Perl, Bash

The intern was founded in XV edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

Education

II.20II - X.20I2

Politechnika Bialostocka (Bialystok, Poland)

Faculty: Computer Studies

Specialization: Smart Internet Technologies

Degree: MSc

Thesis: Analysis tools used to implement the concept of Telco 2.0

The master thesis was carried out in collaboration with <u>Orange Poland S.A.</u> under initiative Orange Labs Telco 2.0 University www.openmiddleware.pl

As the part of the thesis was developed application called Eventoo which aims to monitor the correlation between the area defined by event organizer for instance as a festival and the location of participants based on the operator localization interface to provide statistics and tools to collaborate with them

Framework - Spring (Core, Data, Web)

Database - MongoDB UI - JSP, jQuery

APIs - Orange Location and SMS API, Facebook API

X.20II - II.20I2

Politechnika Lodzka (Lodz, Poland)

Faculty: Technical Physics, Computer Science and Applied Mathematics Specialization: Systems in management and electronic commerce

Degree: MSc

The semester has been completed as part of a student exchange program called MOSTECH intended for students of technical universities

X.2007 - II.20II

Politechnika Bialostocka (Bialystok, Poland)

Faculty: Computer Studies

Specialization: Designing Application Systems

Degree: BSc

Thesis: Secure communication using SMS

Platform - Java ME

Cryptographic algorithms - DES, AES

Scholarships

III.2010 - II.2011 Scholarship at Politechnika Bialostocka

X.20II - II.20I2 University President Scholarship at Politechnika Bialostocka

Certifications

II.2018 Bloomberg Market Concepts (BMC)

V.2016 ScrumMaster by Scrum Alliance (License no. 000527091)

XI.2015 | Java SE 7 Programmer I (1Z0-803)

Languages

Polish: native

English: upper-intermediate

Additional

Winner of XV, XVI and XVII edition of competition "Grasz o Staż" https://www.facebook.com/graszostaz Driving license category B

Languages | Java 7/8 Frameworks | Spring (Boot, Data, MVC, Cache, Batch, Integration) Databases | Oracle (PL/SQL), MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis NoSQL | MongoDB

Web Servlets, JSP, JSON, HTML, REST

XML XPath, XQuery, XSLT, JAXB
Application server Apache Tomcat

Persistence | Hibernate, JPA, JDBC, PL/SQL

Message Broker | ActiveMQ

Testing | JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, DbUnit, WireMock, Assert]

Version Control | Git, Subversion

Libraries | Guava, Apache Commons, JodaTime, Lombok

IDE | IntelliJ, Eclipse

Operating Systems | Linux (Ubuntu), Windows Build automation | Maven, Bower, Gulp

Database Migration | Flyway | Cloud | AWS*

Big Data | Apache Kafka*

Virtualisation Docker SDLC Scrum (Agile)

Collaboration BitBucket, JIRA, Confluence Continuous Integration Jenkins, Nexus, SonarQube

Principles | SOLID

Others | Postman, JMeter

Portfolio

Home - http://garciapl.github.io

 $And roid\ Google\ Play\ Apps-http://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=GarciaPL$

GitHub - http://github.com/GarciaPL

Tech Blog - http://garciapl.blogspot.com

^{* -} in progress